# Julian Joseph

I am a senior software/database developer with over 20 years' commercial IT experience. I am self-motivated and enthusiastic with excellent communication and problem-solving skills and a very strong academic and technical background. I am a quick learner and always seeking to improve my existing knowledge and acquire new skills. My record of contract renewals is testament to my ability to fit into a new team quickly and hit the ground running. I am dependable and hard-working, and a good team player with a pragmatic and positive approach.

## **Key Skills**

- Relational Database Design, Development and Implementation with SQL Server
- BI/ETL Development using SSIS/SSRS
- Software design and development using C#/.NET Framework
- Agile Software Development
- Test Driven Development
- Mentoring junior developers and providing clear and concise technical documentation for new team members

#### Qualifications

- Microsoft Professional Program: Introduction to Data Science Certification (2018)
- Microsoft Professional Program: Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI (2019)
- UKSIP Level 3 Certificate in Investment Management
- Microsoft Certified Solution Developer (MCSD including SQL Server)
- Lloyd's of London Introductory Test
- Markit EDM Introduction Certification & UI Workflow Certification
- MSc (Distinction) Information Systems Design University of Westminster
- BSc (Honours) Zoology University of Leeds

### **Recent Employment Experience**

# Age UK - Data Integration Developer - April 2018 - present

Lead Developer working on the charity's CRM (Customer Relationship Management) BI Data Warehouse platform. This is implemented using a SQL Server 2012 database, populated by data from a variety of external sources using SSIS. The warehouse records all interactions with the charity, and is key to providing performance reporting and driving marketing campaigns. My main remit is to take an overview of the existing system and processes and target areas for improvement or refactoring.

- SQL Server 2012
- SSIS and SSRS
- Source Code control with GIT/BitBucket/TortoiseGit

## Work Break - January 2018 - April 2018

Took a short break between roles to pursue various personal IT-related projects

## Nomura International - Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) July 2015 - January 2018

Lead Developer on a global Product Control project, providing analysis and reporting on Front Office vs Middle Office reconciliation, price verification and testing and end of day position reporting. Working with a team based in London and Mumbai, the application was delivered using the following technologies and approaches:

- C# .NET using Visual Studio 2015
- SQL Server database with Entity Framework Code First
- Microservices using NancyFx and Web API
- Agile Methodology using daily scrums and sprints
- Test Driven Development using MSTest/Resharper Test Runner
- Continuous Integration using Team City

## My responsibilities included:

- Design and development of software and database components
- Providing ongoing technical support and issue resolution for deployed software
- Running daily scrum when required and mentoring and performing code reviews with junior off-shore developers
- Authoring technical documentation
- Building a component to interface with an external SSAS Cube using custom MDX queries
- Building reusable C# ETL components to import CSV files into SQL Server database

## UBS Global Asset Management - Senior BI Analyst/Developer (Contract) March 2015 - July 2015

Working in UBS Global Asset Management Risk Control IT Team. Developing, maintaining and supporting a Risk Reporting Data Warehouse system. Fund data and externally provided analytics data was consolidated using Markit EDM (ETL tool), then exported to an Oracle data warehouse. This drove a Business Objects Universe which allowed Risk Analysts to create and run their own reports.

## Threadneedle Asset Management – Senior SQL Server/BI Developer (Contract) August 2012 – March 2015

#### **Main Projects**

<u>Project Arrow</u>: Migration of Threadneedle's transfer agency to a new provider – including design, build and integration of new feeds into existing client holding data warehouse using SSIS; optimisation and tuning of existing SQL Server 2012 data warehouse to improve performance.

<u>Project Robin</u>: Design and build a new data mart to support Front Office reporting requirements built in SSRS, and ensure seamless integration of re-structured data sources resulting from migration of Threadneedle's outsourced back office services to a new provider

## Nomura International – Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) November 2010 – August 2012

A Senior developer within the Finance Technology Product Control team. Worked on a strategic project to implement a new PnL reporting and reconciliation tool for global deployment in Nomura.

Main responsibilities included design and development of SSIS packages and stored procedures to perform ETL processes with PnL data; investigation and resolution of production issues; designing and deploying tools for use by Environment Management staff.

## Royal Bank of Scotland - Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) April 2010 - October 2010

Member of Global Banking Prime Brokerage IT Team. Worked on streamlining new client onboarding process, and rationalisation of existing clients using SQL Server, SSIS and RBS in-house products.

## Nomura International - Senior Analyst/Developer (Contract) November 2005 - March 2010

Member of Middle and Back Office Technology team. Worked on a wide range of intranet-based global applications within the Corporate, Finance and Operations functions of the bank, mainly implemented using ASP.NET and SQL Server. Key responsibilities included:

- Analysis/design of new projects
- Extending, modifying and enhancing existing applications
- Trouble-shooting and bug-fixing
- User support
- Mentoring users/developers from global offices

## ReformIS Solution Architects - Senior Consultant - September 2004 - October 2005

## Client Assignments:

## New Star Asset Management (September 2004 – September 2005)

Developed a SQL Server/SSIS-based system to administer an investment portfolio management service. Managed all technical aspects of the project, including authoring functional and technical specifications, systems architecture, design and implementation of database, website and web-based components, training and documentation for New Star users and support staff

## Rank Group Gaming Division (July 2004 - September 2004)

Developed and implemented an Operational Reporting system providing detailed analysis of bingo hall visit data held in the Rank data warehouse. The system was deployed nationally to all Mecca Club Managers. Designed and developed custom components using SSRS API to manage a suite of weekly reports, ASP.NET/C# web interface, and SQL Server 2000 objects required to extract and aggregate data efficiently from Rank data warehouse

# Other Personal Projects – January 2018 – April 2018

- Writing a technical blog: <a href="https://julianjoseph.github.io/">https://julianjoseph.github.io/</a>
- Volunteering at my local Code Club (https://www.codeclub.org.uk) helping children learn how to code using Scratch, Python & HTML
- Redesign and development of my cycling club's website (Dulwich Paragon <a href="http://www.dulwichparagon.com/">http://www.dulwichparagon.com/</a>)
- Learning MongoDB, Python and Python web development using Flask
- Various Raspberry Pi projects
- Keeping abreast of other technologies via PluralSight courses (<a href="https://www.pluralsight.com/">https://www.pluralsight.com/</a>)